<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jake Boggs</title>
    <link>https://boggs.tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jake Boggs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://boggs.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Translating Historical Manuscripts with Gemini 3</title>
      <link>https://boggs.tech/posts/translating-manuscripts-with-gemini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://boggs.tech/posts/translating-manuscripts-with-gemini/</guid>
      <description>An app for transcribing and translating historical manuscripts using Gemini 3 and GPT-5.2. Built to impress my girlfriend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable Reinforcement Learning with LLMs - Atropos Guide</title>
      <link>https://boggs.tech/posts/atropos-guide-reinforcement-learning-with-llms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://boggs.tech/posts/atropos-guide-reinforcement-learning-with-llms/</guid>
      <description>Quick intro to Atropos, the RL framework from Nous Research. Written while prepping for their hackathon, where I got 2nd place with an environment for teaching LLMs to write jokes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Reasoning in LLMs Through MTG Deck Building</title>
      <link>https://boggs.tech/posts/evaluating-llm-reasoning-with-mtg-deck-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://boggs.tech/posts/evaluating-llm-reasoning-with-mtg-deck-building/</guid>
      <description>ManaBench is my benchmark for testing LLM reasoning using Magic: The Gathering deck building. Models are tasked with picking the best card from 6 options to complete a deck.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Manamorphosis: A Diffusion Model for MTG Deck Generation</title>
      <link>https://boggs.tech/posts/manamorphosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://boggs.tech/posts/manamorphosis/</guid>
      <description>I trained a diffusion model to complete Magic: The Gathering decklists. Give it some cards, it fills in the rest. Trained on 47k tournament decks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gait Analysis for Physical Therapy with YOLOv11</title>
      <link>https://boggs.tech/posts/gait-analysis-physical-therapy-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://boggs.tech/posts/gait-analysis-physical-therapy-research/</guid>
      <description>Built a video analysis tool for my mom&amp;rsquo;s physical therapy research. Uses YOLOv11-pose for automatic joint detection with a drag-to-correct interface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AccountaBuddy: Your AI Accountability Partner - HackNC 2024</title>
      <link>https://boggs.tech/posts/accountabuddy-hacknc-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://boggs.tech/posts/accountabuddy-hacknc-2024/</guid>
      <description>Weekend hackathon project that calls your phone to check on your tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Yap: A Synthetically Generated Conversational Audio Dataset</title>
      <link>https://boggs.tech/posts/synthetic-conversational-audio-generation-daily-yap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://boggs.tech/posts/synthetic-conversational-audio-generation-daily-yap/</guid>
      <description>Built a 90-hour conversational audio dataset for training multimodal models. Used GPT-4o to clean up Daily Dialog transcripts and XTTS v2 to synthesize speech with 8 different voices. Available on HuggingFace.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models for Magic: the Gathering</title>
      <link>https://boggs.tech/posts/large-language-models-for-magic-the-gathering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://boggs.tech/posts/large-language-models-for-magic-the-gathering/</guid>
      <description>One of my early attempts at making LLMs understand MTG. Created a dataset of 80k question-answer pairs covering card text, rulings, and combos, then fine-tuned Llama 3 8B with QLoRA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://boggs.tech/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://boggs.tech/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Jake and I have a snake. Currently working full-time at &lt;a href=&#34;https://endeavorai.com/&#34;&gt;Endeavor&lt;/a&gt;. I post here occassionally to share my thoughts and projects that I build.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Still new to the Bay Area, hit me up if you want to get coffee and chat. Or calzones. I fucking love calzones.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; flex-wrap: wrap; justify-content: center; gap: 1rem; align-items: flex-start;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://boggs.tech/images/jake.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jake&#34; style=&#34;width: 300px; min-width: 250px; max-width: 90%; margin: 0;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;div style=&#34;width: 300px; min-width: 250px; max-width: 90%;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://boggs.tech/images/snake.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Snake&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; margin: 0;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;^ this guy is Fido&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;span id=&#34;crocs&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chances are that if you see me in the wild, I&amp;rsquo;ll be rocking these:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Startups</title>
      <link>https://boggs.tech/startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://boggs.tech/startups/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page has been up for a while but I recently realized I had never written an explanation of why it exists: I&amp;rsquo;ve always had an irrational fear of getting stuck - not just in a claustrophobic sense, but also in life. That&amp;rsquo;s partially why I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawn to startups. Every day is something new and you must constantly learn and grow, or die. There are many other more &amp;ldquo;college-essay / job-application appropriate&amp;rdquo; aspects I enjoy too (solving problems, building things, ownership etc are great), but this fear more than anything has been the biggest driver. That, coupled with a strong belief that following conventional wisdom will give you conventional outcomes, motivated me to drop out of college with a semester left when I received an offer from a company I truly believe in. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do it for the sake of being contrarian, but because I could see two futures: one where the company succeeded and the degree wouldn&amp;rsquo;t matter, and another where even if didn&amp;rsquo;t go how I expected, I would still learn more than in my remaining classes. Also, witnessing the speed at which AI is improving at coding (and the other assignments too) has given me a bleak outlook on the long-term value of degrees in general. The remaining alpha for humans seems to be in gaining intuition (another word for taste IMO) for things that are difficult to simulate - anything that can be learned easily online has already or will soon be mastered by LLMs. With that said, here are the startups I&amp;rsquo;m most proud to be / have been a part of:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
