<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jake Boggs</title>
    <link>https://boggs.tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jake Boggs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 23:39:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://boggs.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Large Language Models for Magic: the Gathering</title>
      <link>https://boggs.tech/posts/large-language-models-for-magic-the-gathering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 23:39:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://boggs.tech/posts/large-language-models-for-magic-the-gathering/</guid>
      <description>Magic: The Gathering (MTG) has always fascinated me with its complexity and strategic depth, thanks to its extensive rulebook and vast array of unique cards. Despite the game&amp;rsquo;s popularity, AI systems specifically designed for MTG have been few and far between, often falling short due to their inability to accurately interpret the intricate rules and interactions between cards. This blog post chronicles my recent endeavor to bridge this gap with large language models (LLMs) by creating a specialized dataset and evaluation metric to improve AI performance in MTG-related tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Various companies I&#39;ve created or invested in</title>
      <link>https://boggs.tech/startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://boggs.tech/startups/</guid>
      <description>Personal These are companies I&amp;rsquo;ve started myself or been involved with from the beginning. Free Lunch (Cofounder)Small-scale hedgefund, yes I know our website is ugly don&amp;#39;t @ me
Aeternum Analytics (Founder)Began with facial recognition, ended up selling trading cards. Biggest pivot since The Boring Company switched to flamethrowers
Osmos LearnService for K-12 teachers that uses GPT-4V to scan assignments and automatically grade them based on a rubric. Currently on hold due to new student privacy regulations.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
